The carousel is a very interesting Bootstrap complement.
轮播是一个非常有趣的 Bootstrap 组件
It presents a list of scrolling images on the screen.
它能将一系列图像在屏幕上 滚动着显示
So as the images scroll one by one on the screen,
事实上 使用轮播是一个相当方便的
it adds a lot of dynamism to your website.
为你的网站加入动态效果的方式
Now of course, sometimes you might find it to be too distracting, but let's anyway
当然有时你可能会觉得它太花哨了
explore the carousel components to understand how we can configure it.
不过不管怎么说 接下来让我们 学习轮播组件的相关知识吧
Of course, as you realize the carousel component is a JavaScript-based component,
首先你要知道 轮播组件是一个 基于 JavaScript 的组件
and so would require JavaScript support for it to work correctly.
所以为使其正确运作 我们要引入相应的 JavaScript 支持
We're gonna go to the index route HTML page and add a carousel component.
接下来我们要在 index.html 的抬头 或说在其超大屏幕之下
At the top of the page, right after the restaurant's title, below the Jumbotron.
加入一个轮播组件
Taking a look at the index.html page I want to
让我们来到 index.html 中
introduce the carousel right after the jumbotron vec.
我将会在这个超大屏幕下面 引入一个轮播
I'm going to take the content from the remaining three columns,
我将会把主体内容中剩下三列的内容
the content columns of this page and then move it into the carousel.
移到轮播中
Or rather I will just copy it into the carousel.
事实上我有打算直接把代码拷过去
The carousel will be in its own row at the top of the content part of the page.
轮播将会出现在这超大屏幕之下
After I design the carousel, we'll look at the entire web page, and
当我们实现完轮播后 我们会回来看看其效果
then you can decide whether you like the carousel better or to present
然后你可以看看你是更喜欢轮播
the information in the form of consecutive rows as we are doing at this moment.
还是更喜欢现在这个样式
But in any case, the carousel is an interesting component.
不过不论如何 轮播都是一个 有趣的组件
So let's explore that to understand how it works.
所以让我们来学习其实现吧
Going to the HTML code I'm going to introduce another row,
来到 HTML 代码这里 我将会实现另一个 content row
a content row, inside the container here and
也就是一个设置了 class="row row-content" 的 div
inside this content row I'm going to introduce the carousel.
然后我会把轮播放在这个 div 中
So as you can see I have already added the content row and
你可以看到我把代码贴了上来
set up a div inside to expand the entire 12 columns.
然后对第二层 div, 我对其设置了 class="col-xs-12" 以占满所有的 12 列
Now, inside this inner div, I'm going to introduce the carousel.
然后这第二层 div 之内 就是我实现轮播的地方
Let me introduce the basic code for the carousel, and
让我先把代码贴上来
then we will look at the code in more detail.
然后我们再来看它是怎么运作的
To set up a carousel, I need to introduce a div with
首先是一个设置了
a class carousel and a class slide attached to this div.
class="carousel slide" 的 div
I'm going to give, this div and Id as my carousel, and
我还把其 id 设置为了 mycarousel
then also a data attribute as data-ride carousel.
以及设置了 data-ride="carousel"
Inside this div, I have introduced another div with
然后在这个 div 中 我加进了另一个 div
the class carousel-inner and with the role list box.
对这个 div 我设置了 class="carousel-inner"
This carousel-inner contains all the information
然后这个 div 中将会包含所有
that will be displayed on the carousel.
轮播将要展示的内容
Inside this div,
在这个 div 里面
we will introduce each item within the carousel as a div with the class item.
我们要把每一项要展示的内容 封装进一个设置了 class="item" 的 div 中
One of these divs will be designated as active, so
然后对其中一个 div 还要追加设置 class="active"
that is the one that the carousel will begin with.
这个设置表明当轮播刚开始运作时 该 div 对应的内容将会第一个被呈现
Inside the item class, I can include an image.
我们可以在我们要展示的内容中 通过 img 标签加进一个图像
So what I have done here is to take the image that we already have for the dish
你可以看到我已经把我们之前 引入过的那些菜的图片所对应的代码
that we introduced earlier, and then I just pasted that image information here.
都贴到了这里
Together with the image, I can also have a caption being displayed for
然后除了图像之外
that carousel slide there.
我还引入了对图像的说明
So, that is what I am supporting using the div inside there with the class
所以我在这里放了一个设置了
carousel-caption.
class="carousel-caption" 的 div
Now, inside the div carousel-caption I can include HTML code.
我可以在这个 div 里面放 相应的菜的信息
So, what I have done is to take the information from my first row,
事实上你也可以看到
and then cut and paste it inside this div here.
我把相应的菜的信息的代码 都贴了过来
Now, the same thing I'm going to do for two more items in the carousel.
首先我把第一行的菜对应的信息贴了过来
So, the second item corresponds to the second row of our existing HTML page,
然后是第二行的
the image and the information from there.
然后是第三行的
And the third item corresponds to the third image from,
对每一行的菜 要注意把它的 图像对应的代码和信息对应的代码分开
rather, the third row from our existing web page.
图像对应的代码可以直接贴过来 信息对应的代码则需封装在一个 div 中
After introducing these three items,
当我们把这三道菜对应的代码 都贴好了之后
we need to go and fix a few things in our CSS file so
我们还需要对我们的 CSS 文件 做一些小小的更改
that the carousel is properly displayed on the screen.
从而使我们的轮播能够 正确地在屏幕上显示
Moving to the mystyles.css file,
进入到我们的 mystyles.css 文件
I have introduced a few additional CSS classes there.
我已经引入了一些 CSS 类
Let's take a quick look at them, and
让我们快速地看看它们
then understand what these CSS classes are setting up.
并了解它们有啥用
The first CSS class is of course carousel, for
第一个引入 CSS 类是 carousel 类
which I am setting up the background as a dark indigo color.
我设置了 background: #1A237E 意味着我将其背景色设为了深靛蓝色
This is the same color that I'm using for my nav bar, the highlighted
这是因为这个颜色 正是我们导航栏的颜色
part of the nav bar, there, just to match the color schemes.
从而我们的页面看上去色调是一致的
So, I'm using the same color for the colors of background.
事实上在设计页面时 保持色调的一致性相当重要
Now that inside the carousel's individual items I have set up
然后对 .carousel .item 组件
their height to be 300 pixels.
我将其高度设置为了 300 像素
So my carousel's height will now be fixed.
由此 我们轮播的高度就会被固定下来
And the item's image that I include in the carousel, I am specifying
接下来是 .item img 类 这是拿来定制轮播中的图像的
its position as absolute, with the top left corners being set to 0, 0.
我将其定位设置为了绝对定位 以及将左上角的坐标设置为了 0, 0
So, this image that I include there will be stuck on the left edge of this
这意味着轮播中的图像会 贴在轮播的左边缘
carousel slide, with the top and left at point 0, 0.
同时左上角坐标为 0, 0
So the top corner and the left corner of the image aligned with the top zero and
从而图像会贴在
left zero corner of the slide.
轮播的左上角
And I have specified the image's minimum height to be 300 pixels.
我还将图像的最小高度 设置为了 300像素
So no matter what kind of a range I put in there,
从而无论图像本身大小如何
the height will be appropriately at least given to 300 pixels.
该轮播都会将图像的高度 至少拉伸到 300 像素
If you include a larger image then obviously the cursor will stretch to
如果你引入了一个更大的图像的话 那么就会是轮播自身
include the larger image Now, with these changes, let's go and
进行合适的拉伸以包含该图像
take a look at the web page and understand how the carousel behaves on our web page.
那么做完这些改动后 让我们回到我们的网页并看看效果吧
Returning to our web page,
回到我们的网页来
you can now see the carousel in place in the web page in its own room.
你可以看到这里有一个轮播
Now, I have put my mouse cursor on the carousel, so the carousel is now stuck.
如果我将鼠标悬停在轮播上 那么这个轮播就不会继续滚动
So, if I remove the mouse cursor from the carousel it will start sliding left
如果我将鼠标移开
after a certain delay.
该轮播就会继续以一定时间间隔 来继续滚动
The default delay here is three seconds.
默认的时间间隔为三秒
So every three seconds, the slide will move to the left.
也就是说每隔三秒 轮播中的内容 就会更新一次
So this is the behavior of the carousel.
那么这就是轮播的效果
Now, I'm gonna introduce two new controls in to the close.
接下来我将实现两个 对该轮播的控制
The first control will show three dots
第一个控制是在轮播底部显示三个点
towards the bottom of the carousel, which will help me to select whichever slide
每个点对应着一张轮播中的幻灯片
item from the carousel that is displayed on the screen.
通过点击对应的点 就可以让轮播跳到对应的幻灯片
The second control that I will introduce is a left and a right button
第二个控制是在轮播的左右 各引入一个按钮
on the left edge and the right edge of the carousel, so that I can click them and
当我们点击它们时
then manually make the carousel go left and right.
轮播就会向左或向右滚动一下
So, first let me introduce the carousel indicators here.
那么 先让我实现那三个点 或说是轮播的指示器吧
So, within the carousel I am using an ol class here.
那么在轮播里面 我放了一个 ol 标签 同时 我对其设置了
With the class set as carousel-indicators,
class="carousel-indicators"
and then inside here, I have specified three list items, each of these
然后在 ol 中 我放了三个 li 标签 对它们的每一个 我都设置了
with the data-target set to mycarousel, which is the ID of the carousel.
data-target="#mycarousel" 和 data-slide-to 属性
And then also the second attribute that I have here is data slide two and
这个属性是拿来指定其导向的 幻灯片的下标的
then specifies which particular slide I should go to zero, one, or two.
如果你想让该指示器 将你导向第一张幻灯片
In this example we have three slides that I have already introduced so
由于下标是从 0 开始的 所以你只需设置
that's why we can have indicators there.
data-slide-to="0" 即可
Show which slide I would be able to go to.
同时 对相应的 li 设置上 class="active"
The next controls that I am introducing into my carousel is that
接下来就是一左一右两个按钮了
two edges of the carousel, two buttons on the left and
当我们点击这两个按钮时
the right edge of the carousel, which when clicked,
该轮播会相应地
will allow me to change the slides manually within the carousel.
向左或向右滚动一下
So to implement that on the left side I am introducing
以左边的按钮为例 实现的方法是应用 a 标签 并对其设置上 role="button"
an a tag acting as a button.
以表示其为按钮
The width of the class is left and carousel-control.
同时还要设置 class="left carousel-control"
And then the href pointing to the mycarousel, the ID of this carousel,
和 href="#mycarousel" 来指向轮播
and the inside where I am using a glyphicon the left chevron for
然后在 a 标签里面 我应用了一个 相应的 glyphicon 图标
this and the other one is the right carousel control.
同理设置好右边的按钮
And also using the right chevron glyphicon.
只要把所有 left 改成 right 就差不多了
Now with these changes, let's go and
做完这些后 让我们回到我们的网页
have a look at our web page to understand how it looks like.
并看看有哪些变化
Going to your webpage,
来到我们的网页
you can now see that at the bottom you have now three dots here.
你可以看到轮播下面有三个点
One of them filled dot and the remaining two are unfilled dots.
其中一个是填充了的点 另外两个则是空心的
These allow me to select which slide I want to view.
这三个点正是该轮播的指示器
So, for example, if I want to go to the third slide, I can just click on that, and
比如如果我想看第三张幻灯片
then it'll show me the third slide, or the second slide, and so on.
我只需点击这第三个点即可
So these indicators allow me to navigate through
这些指示器事实上
the slides inside the carousel manually.
就是这个轮播的一个微型导航
Also, you can see that on the left edge and the right edge, you have
同时 你可以看到轮播的左右边缘处
the chevrons displayed here, so these are the left and right controls patterns,
分别有一个向左和向右的小箭头
so I can click on this to go to the next slide on the right side.
当我点击向右的箭头时 轮播会滚向下一张幻灯片
Similarly, I can click on this to go to the previous slide on the left side.
同样的 如果我点击向左的这个箭头 轮播就会向前滚动一下
So this manually allows you to page
总之这些功能
through the various slides with your carousel.
能够让你人工地控制该轮播的表现
But this is an interesting component,
所以说轮播是一个有趣的组件 它为你的网页
and has a little more dynamism to your picture.
加入了一些动态效果 【翻译 - Carefree0910】